aircanadavacations.com 2017-10-25

# Air Canada Vacations | Security & Privacy

Your privacy is of the utmost importance and Air Canada Vacations makes every effort to respect it. You always control the information you provide to Air Canada Vacations when planning your travels, and how it is used. 

The following guidelines will explain how your information is gathered, protected and used on the Air Canada Vacations Web site.

##### What kind of information will Air Canada Vacations collect about me?

 Air Canada Vacations will collect personal information from you when you become an Air Canada Vacations member, complete your personal profile, book travel, answer a survey, and enter a contest or sweepstakes.

**Becoming an Air** **Canada** **Vacations member**

To become an Air Canada Vacations member, you will be asked to fill out a registration form with your first name, last name, preferred language of correspondence, closest airport, e-mail address, password, password hint, mailing address (street number, apt/suite, street name), and telephone number, optional fields such as your birthday and preferences are only to personalize your online experience.

Air Canada Vacations needs this information for various reasons, including:

  * identifying you as a member
  * making air, car, and resort hotel reservations
  * contacting you, if necessary 
  * tailoring the Air Canada Vacations Web site to meet your personal needs
  * improving Air Canada Vacations' services 
  * Air Canada Vacations will use your e-mail address to confirm your new membership and any reservations you book on-line and, send newsletters, if you wish to receive them. 

**Your Personal Profile**

Air Canada Vacations can automatically fill certain sections of your travel booking information once you have indicated your travel preferences, ticket delivery address, and other personal information.

**Purchasing Your Vacation Packages Online**

You can purchase vacation packages on the Web site by providing Air Canada Vacations with the billing address, number, type, cardholder name, and expiration date of the credit card you use when booking on-line.

When you purchase a vacation package for a companion through Air Canada Vacations, personal information about that individual will be collected.

Top

##### Will Air Canada Vacations share my information with anyone else?

When you book vacation packages on-line, Air Canada Vacations will only provide the necessary information about you to the airline, car rental agency, hotel, or other third parties, in order to complete your travel arrangements and ensure your experience is a pleasant one. 

Air Canada Vacations has a unique partnership with Aeroplan®, offering you the opportunity to earn miles on your Aeroplan® account for purchases made online with Air Canada Vacations. Air Canada Vacations is required to exchange information with Aeroplan® in order to ensure that your account is maintained and that Air Canada Vacations earned miles are credited and debited correctly. The information exchanged is limited to what is necessary to meet this purpose. 

Air Canada Vacations will provide personal information for products and services purchased or reserved on the Air Canada Vacations Web site to companies acting as agents (suppliers such as Air Canada, hotels, car rental companies) on behalf of Air Canada Vacations in order to provide the requested service. The information will not be shared for marketing purposes nor will Air Canada Vacations sell or distribute members' information to third parties, other than as outlined in this policy.

Please note that third party partners may have privacy policies and practices that differ from those in effect for Air Canada Vacations. We encourage you to review each partner's policy and procedures for collecting, using, and disclosing your information. Air Canada Vacations will occasionally share aggregated information with our service providers. This data is anonymized consequently, it does not contain any personal information, and is used strictly to develop the site.

Air Canada Vacations will also occasionally share aggregated information with our service providers. This data does not contain any personal information, and is used strictly to develop the site.

Top

##### How will Air Canada Vacations use my information?

**Contests and surveys**

As an Air Canada Vacations member, you can enter various contests to win prizes. When entering, you will be asked to provide your contact information so that Air Canada Vacations may notify you in the event of your winning a prize.

You may choose to provide your opinions and comments via surveys, which collect information to enhance and improve Air Canada Vacations' services. All participants will remain anonymous unless otherwise stated and only Air Canada Vacations will have access to the information.

**Our use of Cookies**

Cookies are files stored locally in your web browser, which contain identifiable information about you and your visit.

We use cookies to remember information you gave us, so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit. They also help us understand which areas of our site are popular, so we can make the site and your experience better.

Cookies will remain on your device until you manually remove them, or until they expire.

**Google Analytics**

We use Google Analytics on our website to track your actions and to help us optimize our site for conversions and usability. While we can see data gathered over a timeframe, we do not collect personally identifiable information from any source as part of the terms of service of Google Analytics.

Data collected by Google for the purposes of Google Analytics will be treated according to [Google’s Privacy Policy]{http://www.google.com/privacy/privacy-policy.html}. If you would like to opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics, then you can do so using the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on]{<http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>}.

**Advertising**

We partner with a third party (including Google AdWords, Facebook and Instagram) to advertise our website and services through third party vendors (including Google and DoubleClick) to prospective customers, occasionally using the re-marketing feature to target and advertise to people that may have completed certain actions on our website (tracked through the use of cookies).

An example is if you added a hotel to your shopping cart, but didn’t complete checkout, we may show you advertisements for a period of time to encourage you to come back and complete your booking.

Data collected will be used in accordance with the [Google privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/privacy-policy.html) for Google ads and the Google display network and the [Facebook Cookies Policy](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/).

If you would like to opt out of interest-based advertising, then you can do so using the [Google Ad Preferences](http://www.google.com/settings/ads) and the [Facebook Ad Settings](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences).

**Email “Beacons”**

Air Canada Vacations uses "web beacons" (sometimes called "web bugs"), tiny 1 pixel by 1 pixel images in the emails we send to you. These let us know when and how often you open our emails and whether the unsubscribe or forward features are used.

The beacon also allows "click tracking." Click tracking records what link(s) you click on.

The purpose of tracking this activity is to allow us to make your emails more meaningful to you and improve your overall travel experience with Air Canada Vacations.

**IP Addresses**

IP addresses are logged with each transaction on Air Canada Vacations for the protection of corporate data and member information, such as full name, username, e-mail address, contact information, etc. and the information is kept for 3 months. Please note that this privacy policy does not extend to any links beyond the Air Canada Vacations site.

Top

##### How can I manage what information and marketing communications Air Canada Vacations will offer to me?

Air Canada Vacations email offers  
When you book your travel at aircanadavacations.com you are added to our email list that will be used to contact you monthly with offers that we feel will be of interest to you. If you do not want Air Canada Vacations to contact you with offers you may withdraw your consent at any time simply by changing your profile information and opting out. In addition, all emails sent to you by Air Canada Vacations contain simple instructions telling you how to "unsubscribe."

If you subscribed to our newsletters, you will occasionally receive e-mail about promotions, hot deals, new products or services and personalized news items. Air Canada Vacations' intent is to deliver information that is interesting, exciting and informative. However, we understand and respect that you may prefer not to receive such information. You can update your personal profile to opt-out of this communication in the future by visiting the "My Profile" section on Air Canada Vacations' web site, or by following the instructions on electronic mail and newsletters.

Top

##### How can I access the information I give to Air Canada Vacations and how can I update my personal profile?

Members can view and/or update any information in their personal profile at any time by visiting the "My Profile" section on the Air Canada Vacations Web site.

Top

##### How does Air Canada Vacations protect my information?

All the information you provide to Air Canada Vacations is transmitted using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption, a proven coding system that enables your browser to automatically encrypt (scramble) data before it is sent.

Top

##### Is there anything else I should know about the Air Canada Vacations Privacy Policy?

Please remember that you are responsible for maintaining the security of your passwords. If you share access to a computer remember to log out when you are finished to ensure others do not gain access to your account information. 

Air Canada Vacations is not responsible for the protection of your privacy on links beyond the Air Canada Vacations Web site. Please read each site's individual privacy statements, as their policies and practices may differ from Air Canada Vacations'.

Air Canada Vacations may disclose members' personal information under certain circumstances: 

  * when required by law 
  * when requested by certain government authorities whose enabling legislation permits such requests 
  * when deemed necessary to protect the rights or properties of Air Canada Vacations 

Top

##### How can I manage what information and marketing communications Air Canada Vacations will offer to me?

As an Air Canada Vacations member that has subscribed to our newsletters, you will occasionally receive e-mail about promotions, hot deals, new products or services and personalized news items. Air Canada Vacations' intent is to deliver information that is interesting, exciting and informative. However, we understand and respect that you may prefer not to receive such information. You can update your personal profile to opt-out of this communication in the future by visiting the "My Profile" section on Air Canada Vacations' web site, or by following the instructions on electronic mail and newsletters.

If you elect not to receive any e-mail with Air Canada Vacations offers or travel promotions, Air Canada Vacations will only use your e-mail address to confirm travel purchases electronically. You can also unsubscribe to any other promotional offers or deals by replying to the e-mail with the word "unsubscribe" in the subject line.

Top

##### How does Air Canada Vacations communicate changes about their privacy practices and policy?

Any material changes to the Air Canada Vacations Privacy Policy will be published in this privacy statement, on the Air Canada Vacations homepage and other places we deem appropriate, so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

Additionally, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our website notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post a notice we will also email users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.

Top

##### How do I contact Air Canada Vacations if I have questions about this privacy policy?

Please email any questions or comments regarding this Privacy Policy to Privacy@vacv.com and be sure to include "Privacy Policy" in your subject line. Air Canada Vacations will try to answer all reasonable inquiries within five business days.

**Transparency**

Air Canada Vacations ensures that its Privacy Policy concerning the management of personal information is readily accessible to any person and especially to its members. Air Canada Vacations makes available copies of this Policy, which may be obtained at any time by addressing a request for this purpose to the AIR CANADA VACATIONS Privacy Officer.

**Access to personal information**

On request, any person is entitled to be informed of the existence of personal information held by AIR CANADA VACATIONS regarding that person, the use that is made of it and whether this information has been disclosed to third parties. A person is also entitled to consult the information held by AIR CANADA VACATIONS regarding that person, subject to the exceptions prescribed by law. A person may also contest the accuracy or completeness of the information and request that corrections be made to it. To exercise rights of access or rectification, individuals may the AIR CANADA VACATIONS Privacy Officer at the following address: Air Canada Vacations, 1440 St. Catherine St. West, Suite 600, Montreal, Quebec, H3G 1R8

Individual applicants must identify themselves, and sign their applications so as to prevent fraud or the unjustified transmission of personal information to third parties. Individuals must provide sufficient information so that it is possible for AIR CANADA VACATIONS to inform them of the existence, use and disclosure of personal information.

AIR CANADA VACATIONS processes applications for access to or rectification of personal information within thirty (30) days of receipt of the application. This deadline may be extended by an additional period of thirty (30) days when processing of the application would seriously impede AIR CANADA VACATIONS' activities or the circumstances or scope of the application make it impossible to comply with this deadline.

In general, AIR CANADA VACATIONS does not charge any fee for allowing a person to have access to the personal information held regarding that person and to obtain rectification of information. However, reasonable fees may be charged when the application for access or rectification is complex.

AIR CANADA VACATIONS rectifies personal information to the extent that the person concerned establishes the incompleteness or inaccuracy of the information. Rectification may involve correction or deletion of the information or the addition of supplementary information.

If the person concerned is not satisfied with the response provided to an application for access or rectification, the person may file a complaint with the AIR CANADA VACATIONS Privacy Officer.

 **Complaints regarding non-observance of the Policy**

A member may complain to AIR CANADA VACATIONS where the member feels there has been non-compliance with this Policy and the commitments regarding privacy and the rules it contains by applying to the AIR CANADA VACATIONS Privacy Officer.

A complaint or a request for an investigation may be addressed in writing to the AIR CANADA VACATIONS Privacy Officer at the following address: Air Canada Vacations, 1440 St. Catherine St. West, Suite 600, Montreal, Quebec, H3G 1R8

Unless it is manifestly abusive, any complaint or request for an investigation shall be the object of an investigation or a response within sixty (60) business days. If the complaint is justified, AIR CANADA VACATIONS will take appropriate measures to address the complaint, by allowing access to the requested information, by proceeding with rectification or, as the case may be, by amending its Policy and practices.

Top
